mountain.org 2014-06-29

# Privacy Policy | The Mountain Institute

**Privacy Statement:**

The Mountain Institute is committed to preserving your privacy and safeguarding your information online. This privacy policy demonstrates our firm commitment to the privacy of our website users and those who contribute to our organization. This statement explains what types of information is collected by our website, [www.mountain.org](http://www.mountain.org/ "www.mountain.org"), and how this information is used. 

**What Personally Identifiable Information is Collected:**

Individuals who register to receive our e-communications and our contributors and supporters provide us with their contact information (such as their names and e-mail addresses).  We may use this information for specific, limited purposes. You may always "opt out," either now or at any time in the future, if you do not wish to receive our emails.  You may also request us to discontinue sending communications to you by mail.  To “opt out” or discontinue such mailings, please contact us as explained below.

**IP addresses:**

The Mountain Institute uses your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer [www.mountain.org](http://www.mountain.org/ "www.mountain.org"), and for statistical metrics used to track website visitor traffic.

**Cookies:**

www.mountain.org uses "cookie" messages to automatically help provide better services. They remind us who you are and your preferences for our website based on what you've done and told us before. The "cookie" is placed in your computer and is read when you come back to our website. Cookies let us take you to the information and features you're particularly interested in. They also let us track your usage of [www.mountain.org](http://www.mountain.org/ "www.mountain.org"), so we know which parts of our sites are most popular. You can reject cookies or cancel them by instructing your Web browser accordingly.

**How Your Information May Be Used:**

We use your personal information to let you know about our work or upcoming events; to send e-mail alerts to you; to answer your requests; to process your contributions; etc. You may choose to opt out at any time, which will cease all communications from us. We may also use your information to track visitors to our website. This lets us see which of our features are the most popular so we can better serve our users' needs. It also lets us provide aggregate data to others about our traffic (not identifying you personally, but showing how many visitors used which features, for example).

**Security:**

When providing your sensitive information online, such as financial information to make a donation, we will redirect you to a secure server and notify you of this redirect through a pop-up screen. Your credit card information is never stored.

**Email Privacy:**

The Mountain Institute does not provide, sell, or rent email addresses to anyone outside the organization.

**Children’s Guidelines:**

Our website does notknowingly collect identifiable personal information from children under age 13. If we discover that a person under the age of 13 has provided us with any personally identifiable informationthrough our website, we will delete that information from our systems. We are unable to reply to information requests from children under the age of 13, if so identified. A parent or guardian must initiate any requests for information from children under the age of 13 on their behalf. We encourage parents to supervise children when they browse the internet.

**External Links:**

www.mountain.orgincludes links to external websites. These links do not fall under the [www.mountain.org](http://www.mountain.org/ "www.mountain.org")  domain, and The Mountain Institute is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of external websites. Your use of any linked website is solely at your own risk.

**Contact Us:  **

To contact us (to discontinue our communications or for any other reason), please send an email to us using the “Email us” tab in our website homepage.  Alternatively, you may send an email to [summit@mountain.org](mailto:summit@mountain.org), call our offices at 202-234-4050, or write us at The Mountain Institute, Suite 101, 3000 Connecticut Avenue N.W., Washington DC, 20008. 

**Modifications:**

We may amend this privacy statement and our related Fundraising and Donor Privacy Policy from time to time; please review them periodically. We maintain the option to modify these documents and all other policies at any time by electronic notice posted on our website. Your continued use of our website after the date that such notices are posted will be deemed to be your agreement to the changed terms.
